字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
最快首发美剧日剧下载请登录
字幕组网站www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Charl Reginamoon 小暴徒 想名字好难 木浅薰 kahiko Timothy
翻译：dzysteven 杨爱菜 JohnnyG  校对：油炸电风扇   木浅薰
时间轴：壬虚浪影  今  coco
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第六季   第六集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on "Suits"...
因为我已经追查萨特三年了
I've been after Sutter for three years now.
这个狡猾的混蛋
This guy's one slippery son of a bitch.
等等  威廉・萨特吗
Wait a second, William Sutter?
他上周来找过我让我为他辩护
He came to me a week ago to take him on.
你一旦做了任何威胁到我的事
You cross one line that puts me in jeopardy,
我就会把这件事叫停
I'm gonna pull the plug on this whole thing.
我需要在汉普顿买一栋又大又贵的房子
I need a large, expensive home in the Hamptons.
你为什么要买一栋度假住宅
Why are you buying a vacation home?
因为我告诉塔拉・梅瑟
Because I told Tara Messer
我在那里有一处房产
that I have a property out there,
而且我雇了她来重新装修
and I hired her to remodel it for me.
可恶  哈维  我不会在这个案子上和你串通
Damn it, Harvey, I'm not colluding on this,
你居然来这里
and you're in here trying to get me
怂恿我对你自己的客户提起公诉
to bring an indictment against your own client.
因为你提起公诉后  我会打赢官司
Because when you bring that indictment, I'm gonna beat it,
可你不起诉
and if you don't bring it,
且继续调查我的客户  我就会去告你
and continue investigating my client, I'm gonna sue you.
我觉得最可笑的是
I think it's pretty goddamn funny
你口口声声说你不信任我  但你才是那个
that you don't trust me, when you're the one
连进来的原因都不敢告诉我的人
that won't even tell me what you're in here for.
好  我接受
Okay. I'll do it.
-你说什么  -你的法律援助案件
- Excuse me? - Your pro bono.
明早带文件来
Bring me the file tomorrow morning.
你这招接得很漂亮  肖恩
It was a good fix, Sean.
你的招出得也不错  哈维
It was a good move, Harvey.
想去喝一杯吗
Want to get a drink?
不如就在这儿喝怎么样
Why don't we just have one here?
为什么  目前为止
Why? As of right now,
你还没有针对我客户的动作
you have no action pending against my client.
但明早就有了
But as of tomorrow, I do,
因为明早起诉书就要提出了
'cause those indictments are coming down in the morning.
凯文  你做了什么
Kevin, what did you do?
我跟妻子吵了一架
I got in a fight with my wife.
我喝醉了  开着车  差点撞死人
I got drunk. I got into my car, and I almost killed someone.
我错过了上千次早晨抱抱我的孩子的机会
I'm missing 1,000 chances to hug my kids in the morning
晚上亲吻我妻子的机会
and kiss my wife good night,
只是因为我没有控制好自己
all because I couldn't control myself.
你跟你妻子是因为什么吵的架
What were you fighting with your wife about?
我不能说  不能说
I can't. I just can't.
哈维  你在这干什么
Harvey. What are you doing here?
迈克  坐下  我得跟你说件事
Mike, sit down. I need to tell you something.
怎么了
What's going on?
我在想办法把你弄出去
I'm working on getting you out of here.
对  我知道
Yeah, I know you are.
我不是指为卡荷尔做的事
I'm not talking about what we're doing for Cahill.
我是说别的
I'm talking about something else.
哈维  这里这么多人
Harvey, we're in a room full of people.
你不能在这提卡荷尔
You can't be talking about Cahill.
如果凯文知道了
If Kevin finds out--
他现在知道也无所谓了
It doesn't matter if Kevin finds out now.
他完了
He's done.
你说他完了是什么意思
What do you mean, "He's done?"
瑞秋死了
I mean Rachel's dead...
是凯文杀了她
and Kevin killed her.
什么
What?
是真的
It's true.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
你在骗我
You're lying to me.
该死  他跟你说了是他干的
Goddamn it. He told you he did it.
-放屁  -他喝醉了
- Bullshit. - He got drunk.
开着车
He got in a car.
撞死了你爱的女人
He murdered the woman you love.
-别说了  -而你下半辈子
- Stop saying that. - And now you're going
就要跟他一起困在这里了
to be stuck in here with him for the rest of your life.
别说了  凯文不会那么对我的
Stop it. Kevin would never do that to me.
-迈克  醒醒吧  -不
- Mike, wake up. - No.
-迈克  -不
- Mike. - No.
-醒醒  醒醒  -不
- Wake up. Wake up. - No!
-迈克  醒醒  -不不不
- Mike, wake up. - No, no, no, no, no.
迈克  醒醒
Mike, wake up.
你没事吧
Hey, you okay?
-没事  我没事  -你确定
- Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine. - You sure?
你好像做了个很可怕的梦
'Cause that was some dream you were having.
我没事
I'm fine.
我接着睡了
Just going back to sleep.
哈维  太好了  你来了
Harvey, good, there you are.
-怎么了  -萨特刚刚打来
- What's going on? - Sutter just called.
让我猜猜  起诉书出来了吧
Let me guess, the indictments came down?
他一小时之前就要你去他办公室了
He wants you in his office an hour ago.
我去跟他说你在路上了
I'll tell him you're on your way.
不  跟他说你找不到我
No. Tell him you couldn't reach me.
你要他紧张  但是为什么
You want him to start sweating, but why?
因为人一紧张
Because when people start sweating,
就会开始跟他的律师说实话
they start talking to their lawyer.
我让雷去待命
I'll tell Ray to be on hold.
不  让他把车开过来
No, tell him to pull around.
你不是说你不去萨特那边吗
But you just said you weren't going to Sutter's.
的确  我要去别的地方
I'm not. I'm going somewhere else.
看看谁来了  大明星啊
Oh, look who it is, the man of the hour.
-你收到我的起诉书了吗  -当然收到了
- Did you get my indictments? - I sure as hell did.
既然派对已经开始了
Now that the party's started,
你告诉我凯文・米勒知道些什么吧
why don't you tell me what Kevin Miller knows?
-你在说什么  -你咬定这个人
- What are you talking about? - You went after the guy
想要他出卖萨特
to try to get him to flip on Sutter,
你觉得他能给你什么证据
so what'd you think he was gonna give you?
-我才不会告诉你  -为什么
- I'm not gonna tell you that. - Why not?
因为我一开始就跟你说了
Because I told you when I started this thing,
-我不会跟你串通的  -我们这不是串通
- I'm not gonna collude. - We're not colluding.
这叫发现
It's called discovery.
你赶快告诉我  凯文・米勒到底知道些什么
So why don't you tell me what the hell Kevin Miller knows?
凯文设计了一个交易软件
He developed the trading programs
萨特声称是靠那个软件获得了高额回报
that Sutter claims to use to get his superior returns.
那这个软件肯定没什么用
Then that program's got to be full of shit,
不然的话
because if it isn't--
萨特就没有做内部交易
Then Sutter's not inside trading,
而他绝对是做了内部交易
which he sure as shit is.
所以你想要凯文作证
So you're looking to have Kevin testify
那个软件是狗屁  而萨特也是知情的
that software is bullshit, and Sutter knows it.
-没错  -那让我问你
- Bingo. - Then let me ask you this,
你是以什么罪名把凯文抓进去的
what exactly did you put Kevin away for?
你又是为什么要知道答案
And why do you need to know that?
因为这也许可以帮我们弄清楚
Because it might help us figure out
他的弱点是什么
what his weak spot is.
我们给他的罪名是
We got him on vehicular assault while
醉驾撞人
driving under the influence.
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding me?
你之前怎么没想着告诉我们一声
Why didn't you think to tell us that?
我为什么要说
Why would I?
迈克的父母就是被一个醉酒的司机撞死的
Mike's parents were killed by a drunk driver.
我怎么可能知道这一点
And how the hell was I supposed to know that?
我不知道  要是你能在
I don't know. It would have been nice
我们把迈克送回去和他同住之前
to know what this asshole did,
知会我们一声这个混蛋做了什么就好了
before we sent Mike back into a cell with him.
你今早怎么了
Hey, what happened to you this morning?
什么意思
What do you mean?
-你没去吃早餐  -我不饿
- You skipped breakfast. - I wasn't hungry.
-只是因为这个吗  -你想说什么
- That all it was? - What are you talking about?
拜托  迈克  你昨晚做了个噩梦
Come on, Mike, you had a nightmare last night.
然后今早一直在回避我
You've been avoiding me all morning,
现在又表现得很怪异  到底怎么了
and you're acting weird right now--what's going on?
没什么
Nothing's going on.
那你到底为什么吓出了一身冷汗
Then why the hell were you in a cold sweat,
咕哝着什么有人没发现
muttering something about someone not finding out,
然后还喊了我的名字
and then calling out my name?
好吧凯文  你想知道这是怎么回事是吧
All right, Kevin, you want to know what's going on?
我梦见你撞死了瑞秋
I had a dream that you killed Rachel in a car accident.
那也许就是今早
That's probably why I don't particularly
我不太想理你的原因
feel like hanging out with you this morning.
是因为你和我讲过的你父母的事
Because of what you told me about your parents,
-迈克 我真的很抱歉  -真的吗
- Mike, I'm really sorry. - Are you?
这是什么意思
What--what's that supposed to mean?
昨晚你告诉我你差点撞死了一个人
I mean, last night you told me you almost killed someone.
你对此感到抱歉吗
Are you sorry about that?
你在说笑吗
You got to be kidding me.
你做了个梦  然后就来质问我
You have a dream, and now you're questioning
我是否为那晚的事感到抱歉
if I feel bad about what I did that night?
你还没回答我你是否感到抱歉
You still haven't answered whether or not you do.
知道吗  假如你需要冲我发火
You know what? You need to be pissed off
来调节心情  没问题
at me to deal with your shit, you go right ahead.
但我对那晚发生的事感到无比的悔恨
But I feel horrible about what happened that night,
而且我告诉你
and for your information,
我撞的那个人如今已经痊愈了
the guy that I hit is fully recovered right now,
而我却依然在这里赎罪
and I'm still in here paying for this shit.
准备开香槟庆祝吧  路易
Break out the champagne, Louis.
汉普顿的房子九十天之后就是你的了
That house in the Hamptons is gonna be yours into 90 days.
-他们接受我的报价了  -没错
- They accepted my offer? - That they did.
我有比香槟更好的庆祝方式...
Well, then I have something much better than champagne...
木材
Wood.
我真看不出来这怎么就比香槟好了
I don't really see how that's better than champagne.
你当然看不出来
Of course you don't.
因为你不知道我正在为塔拉
Because you don't know that I'm having a replica
搭建一个我房子的模型
of my house made for Tara,
这样她就能看见自己的设计成真了
so she can see her designs come to life.
路易  这一招真甜啊
Louis, that's actually really sweet.
我知道
I know.
现在  我只需要选择完美的木材
Now, all I need to do is pick the perfect wood.
我没明白
I don't follow.
唐娜  你所选择的木材
Donna, the kind of wood you get
能完全展示出
says everything you need to know
你是一个什么样的男人
about what kind of man you are.
是软还是硬
How hard or soft it is.
使用的时候能弯曲到什么程度
How much it bends when you're working it.
以及它是如何的坚定...
How firm it is compared--
我明白了  路易
I got the picture, Louis.
不  我觉得你没明白
No, I don't think you do.
让塔拉爱上我的木材
Making Tara love my wood
是让她爱上我的第一步
is the first step toward making her love me.
-好了  路易  冷静点  -不
- Okay, Louis, calm down. - No.
我并不想冷静下来
I don't really want to calm down,
因为我满脑子都是我的木材
because all I can think about my wood.
那告诉我
So tell me,
你一天之中
exactly how many different kinds of wood
看了多少种不同的木材
have you sampled in your day?
所有品种
All of them.
红木  栗木  胡桃木  各种木
Mahogany, chestnut, walnut, all the nuts.
乌木呢
Ebony?
别给我起乌木这个头
Don't even get me started on ebony.
当我看见乌木时
When I see ebony,
我只想抚摸它
all I want to do is put my hands all over it.
-老天  -我想住在里面
- Oh, God. - I want to live in it.
我想拍它  打它  摩擦它
I want to smack it and hit it, rub it down.
我真想吃了它
I just want to eat it.
有什么好笑的
What's so funny?
没什么...
Nothing. Um...
我只是觉得一个男人应该遵从自己的内心
I just think that a man needs to follow his heart
选择他感觉对的那种木材
and choose the wood that just feels right.
-感觉对的  -没错
- Feels right. - Yeah.
正是如此  唐娜...
That's it. Donna...
我需要你帮我感受我的木材
I need you to help me feel my wood.
老天爷啊
Oh, dear God.
该死的  朱莉
God damn it, Julie,
再给他办公室打一次电话
call his office again,
这次告诉他去找...
and this time tell him to find--
假如你说的是我的办公室
If you're talking about my office,
那就不必打电话了
there's no need.
我来了
I'm right here.
你怎么现在才来
What the hell took you so long?
-我之前没空  -我刚刚被起诉了
- I was unavailable. - Well, I just got indicted,
所以从现在开始  你必须有空
so from now on you make yourself available.
我明白了
I get it.
你刚开始觉得这不是玩笑
This all just got real for you,
所以你现在何不告诉我
so why don't you tell me right now,
其他部分有多真实
how real is the rest of it?
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我在说  卡荷尔声称
I'm saying, Cahill claims
你是赚不到你所赚的利润的
that you can't make the returns you do.
而你说你可以
You say you can,
所以我想知道你是怎么赚到的
and I want to know how you do it.
我们使用了一个自营交易算法
We use a proprietary trading algorithm.
-由谁开发的  -我的女婿
- Developed by who? - My son-in-law.
很好  那我们就可以把这个算法给卡荷尔了
Good, then we can give it to Cahill,
因为他刚刚申请到了传票
'cause he just subpoenaed it.
-不  我们不能给  -为什么
- No, we can't. - Why the hell not?
因为我赚钱最多的那些交易
Because the trades on which I make the most money
和那个程序无关
have nothing to do with that program.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
你在承认自己有内线交易
You're admitting to inside trading?
我什么都没承认  只是有些时候
I'm not admitting to anything, except that sometimes
我的交易靠的是直觉
I trade with my gut.
那么威廉  我要告诉你
Well, I got news for you, William.
你这话在陪审团听来  会觉得你有罪
To a jury, that's gonna sound like you're full of shit.
那好  聪明人  拿起那份报纸
Okay, smart guy, pick up that journal.
说出一支股票的名字
Give me a stock.
纳斯达克  纽约证交所  什么都行
NASDAQ, New York Stock Exchange, I don't give a shit.
随便选一个
Just pick one.
-骏科网络讯息  -骏科网络讯息
- All right, Computech. - Computech.
流通股票15.9亿股
1.59 billion shares outstanding.
昨日收盘于32  比较平稳
Yesterday's close, 32, flat.
今日开盘于33.25
Today's opening, 33 1/4.
市盈率17%
P/E's at 17.
年利润有望增长2%
Earnings expected to grow at 2% a year.
报纸上没说的是
What it doesn't say in there,
公司的利润不会增长
is that the earnings aren't gonna grow,
因为他们的首席执行官并不在乎
because the CEO doesn't give a shit,
这使得这个陷阱充满了迷惑性
which makes it a value trap dressed up like a princess,
我可不会去踩这样的无底洞
and I wouldn't touch it with a ten-foot pole.
你这伎俩很高超  威廉
That's a pretty neat trick, William,
但传票该来还是会来的
but it isn't gonna stop this subpoena.
这不是伎俩  这就是我的本事
It's not a trick. It's what I do.
你需要做的  就是阻止那个混蛋
What you're gonna do, is stop that son of a bitch
让他不要插手我的生意
from getting his hands on my program.
瑞秋  不管有什么事都先等等再说
Rachel, whatever it is, it's going to have to wait.
可你让我把今天早上
Okay, but you told me to bring you everything
把贝利案的所有材料都拿给你
I have on the Bailey case this morning.
很好  放我桌子上吧
Great. Leave it on my desk
我这周抽时间看看
and I'll get to it sometime this week.
抱歉  杰西卡
Oh, I'm sorry, Jessica,
我希望今天就能和你探讨一下案情
I was really hoping that we could go over it today.
我这会急着要出去
I was hoping to be out the door by now.
我知道我说过
Look, I know that I said
这案子不会耽误你太多时间  可是...
this wouldn't take up too much of your time, but...
瑞秋  我都答应你了  肯定会帮忙的
Rachel, I said I would do this, and I will,
-但你一定要有耐心  -我能理解
- but you just have to be patient. - I understand.
可伦纳德・贝利已经等了12年了
It's just, Leonard Bailey's been patient for 12 years.
我同情这个人
And I have sympathy for the man,
但今天不行
but today's not the day.
不用拿菜单了  来份科布沙拉就好
Don't bother with another menu. I'll just have a Cobb salad.
你这是要干什么
What do you think you're doing?
你觉得呢
What does it look like I'm doing?
我正在跟客户共进午餐
I'm having lunch with a client
讨论他的投资业务
to discuss his investment business.
你又没代理我的投资业务
You don't represent my investment business.
所以才应该共进午餐
Which is exactly why we need to have lunch.
不  我们没这个必要
No, we don't need to have anything,
因为我们有协议
'cause the deal was Harvey gets me cleared
哈维帮我扫清刑事诉讼后
of criminal charges,
你才能接管我剩下的业务
then you get the rest of my business.
我不在乎那份之前的协议  威廉
I don't care what the deal was, William.
我在乎的是现在这份
I care what the deal is.
因为眼下你马上就要被起诉了
Because now that that indictment's come down,
哈维的全部精力都会花在你身上
Harvey is going to be spending all of his time on you.
-这与我无关  -那我就把它归结到你身上
- That's not my problem. - I'm making it your problem.
我们接管你的所有业务  不然就此收手
We get all of your business, or we handle none of it.
荒唐
Bullshit.
你们退出  这笔可观的服务费就泡汤了
You quit, you lose billables you can't afford to lose.
我们退出  别人会觉得我们意识到了
We quit, and it looks like we realized
你的案子注定是败局所以想撤退
your case was a loser and wanted distance from it,
这舆论你们也承担不起
which you can't afford.
你真的想以这种方式开始合作关系吗
You really want to start a business relationship this way?
我不在乎如何开始  威廉
I don't give a shit how it starts, William.
我只关心别人怎么看
I give a shit how it looks.
原来你是因为这个才来这
Oh, that's why you did this here.
你想让别人认为  你们已经代理我的公司了
You want it to look like you already represent my firm.
反应够快
Well, look at that.
看来你没雇错人
Looks like I'm worth hiring after all.
那我们究竟是合作呢
So are we actually going to talk business,
还是还是单纯的雇佣关系
or am I just gonna bill you for the pleasure of my company?
什么事  迈克
Mike, what can I do for you?
请你告诉我  你会不会用诚实疗法
You can tell me if you do straight-up therapy or not.
-为什么这么问  -你没回答我的问题
- What's on your mind? - You didn't answer my question.
我觉得没这个必要
I didn't think I needed to,
因为自从你入狱
since we've been doing straight-up therapy
我们一直都采用这种疗法
since you got here.
说吧  找我到底什么事
So, you want to tell me what you're here for?
我十一岁时  父母被一个醉酒的司机撞死了
My parents were killed by a drunk driver when I was 11,
然而昨天我发现
and yesterday I found out that
凯文在醉酒的状态下差点撞死了人
Kevin almost killed someone drunk driving.
因此我想让你帮我  在他面前表现得正常些
So I need you to help me act normal around him,
从而达到我的目的  最终离开这里
so that I can get what I need, so I can get out of here.
问题就出在这
Oh, well, that's gonna be a problem.
因为这种治疗的目的
Because the goal of therapy
不在于表现的正常  而是真正的正常
is not to act normal, it's to be normal.
我回到家跟心爱的女人在一起
Yeah, well, I'll be normal when I'm home
就会正常  也不会梦到
with the woman I love instead of dreaming
跟我住一间牢房的人杀掉了她
that the guy I'm sharing a cell with killed her.
-什么  -我昨晚做了个梦
- What? - I had a dream last night
梦到我不再需要告发凯文了
that I didn't have to inform on Kevin anymore,
因为他在一次事故中杀掉了瑞秋
because he killed Rachel in an accident.
我肯定是做梦的时候说梦话了
And I must have been talking about it in my sleep,
因为他今天问起我了
because he asked me about it today,
我给他讲了事故那段梦  然后我们就吵了起来
so I told him the accident part, and then we got in a fight.
-为什么吵起来  -我问他
- Fight about what? - I asked him
是否因为撞了人感到愧疚
if he even felt bad about the guy he hit.
也就是说你把责任推到了他身上
So you turned it back on him?
你这话什么意思
What is that even supposed to mean?
意思是  我觉得你找茬跟凯文打架
It means that I think you picked a fight with Kevin
因为你自己不愿意思考
because you didn't want to think about
为什么会做那种梦
why you had that dream.
我知道为什么
I know why I had the dream.
是因为他差点撞死别人
It's because he almost killed someone
而我父母就是被撞死的
the same way my parents were killed.
不  你做那梦  是因为你不愿意面对
No, you had the dream, because you don't want to deal
你对朋友的背叛
with what you're doing to your friend.
-又来这套  -没错  就是这套
- Oh, this again. - Yes, this again.
迈克  你觉得在你梦里
Mike, why do you think part of the dream was finding out
不再需要出卖他的原因是什么
that you didn't have to inform on him anymore?
该死  我来这里
God damn it, I did not come here
为的不是质疑我的决定
to second guess my decision.
你知道吗  我不在乎
Do you know what? I don't care.
因为如果我不告诉你这个行为的后果
Because I wouldn't be doing my job,
我就没有尽职尽责
if I didn't inform you that actions have consequences,
但看来你自认为
and you seem to think that
你所作所为的唯一结果
the only consequence of what you're doing
就是能提早出狱  其实不然
is getting out of here early, but it's not.
我觉得你对我所经历的事一无所知
I think you don't know shit about what I've been through.
真不该来找你帮我
It's a mistake coming to you for help.
这是第五个卧室
And this is the fifth bedroom,
我完全不介意你拆墙
and I'm completely open to you knocking down walls
或者封堵窗户
or removing windows, by the way.
不用  我喜欢窗户
No, I love the windows.
-窗户使得光线充足  -我同意
- They let in so much light. - I agree.
我们应该加一面玻璃墙  你觉得呢
We should add a wall of glass. What do you think?
我觉得这个地方太漂亮了
I think the place is beautiful,
谢谢你带来这些照片
and I appreciate you bringing these photos over,
但我们什么时候能亲自去看看
but when can we go see it in person?
-亲自去  -没错
- In person? - Yes, of course.
我得在开始绘图之前看一下空间布局
I need to see the space before I can start drafting anything.
我以为我们在开始之前
I was just thinking we could work closer together
能先紧密合作六十到九十天
for the next 60 to 90 days before you started that.
那样效率太低
That wouldn't be productive.
但我在接下来的七到十个工作日内
But I couldn't possibly make it out there
都去不了那里
in less than seven to ten business days.
那太可惜了
That's too bad.
我本来想后天去那看看的
I was gonna be out there the day after tomorrow.
我以为我们能看看房子
I was thinking we could see the space,
然后吃个午餐什么的
and then maybe go have lunch.
一起吃  午餐
Lunch? Together?
我没想过我们要分开吃饭
Well, I wasn't thinking of eating in separate restaurants.
当然不会
Ha! Of course you weren't.
后天没问题
Day after tomorrow's perfect.
-但我以为你不能  -我能  我会去的
- But I thought you couldn't-- - I can, and I will,
那我们后天下午  在我祖传的
and I will meet you at my ancestral home,
属于我一段时间了的别墅见
that I've owned for quite some time, day after tomorrow.
法官大人  我只是要求萨特先生提交
Your Honor, I'm simply requesting Mr. Sutter hand over--
你没权要求他提交的东西
Something he has not right to.
我有权力确保
I have every right to make sure
你的客户在法律要求范围内进行操作
that your client is operating within the law.
你是基于什么说他不在法律要求范围内呢
And what exactly is your basis to say that he isn't?
法官大人  当你打破本垒打记录
Your Honor, when you break the home run record,
但有人说"你的球棒有问题"时
and someone says, "Your bat is corked,"
你转身给他们看你的球棒并没问题
you turn it over to show it's not.
除非这个球棒正是你击出所有全垒打的原因
Except when that bat is the reason you hit all those homers,
因为一旦他拿到了球棒
because the second he gets it,
全世界的人都知道里面有什么了
everyone in the world's gonna know what's in it.
那我的客户还不如现在直接关门停业得了
And my client might as well go out of business right now.
这是个毫无证据支持的
That is a ridiculous supposition
可笑的假设
without a shred of proof to back it up.
这个证据如何
How's this for proof?
法官大人  六年前
Your Honor, six years ago,
卡荷尔先生做过像这次一样的非法调查
Mr. Cahill went on a fishing expedition just like this one.
这二者毫无关系
That has nothing to do with this.
是吗
doesn't it?
他传讯过凯斯勒投资公司的
He subpoenaed a proprietary trading program
一个自营交易软件
from Kessler Capital.
结果证明没有非法行为
It proved no wrongdoing,
十个月之后  他们就倒闭了
and ten months later they were out of business.
这跟我的传讯毫无关系
That has nothing to do with my subpoena.
我有一份来自凯斯勒先生的宣誓书说
And I have an affidavit here from Mr. Kessler saying
这和你的传讯有直接关系
it was directly because of your subpoena.
卡荷尔先生  他说的是事实吗
Mr. Cahill, is what he's saying true?
你对凯斯勒用过同样的手段
Did you go after Kessler in the same manner,
十个月后他倒闭了吗
and did he go under ten months later?
-是的  但是...  -没有但是
- Yes, but-- - No buts,
你还有其他证据向当庭提供吗
do you have any other evidence to present to the court?
目前没有了  法官大人
Not at this time, Your Honor.
那你的要求被驳回了
Then your request is denied.
原来你在这呢
There you are.
你在行政总厨干什么
What the hell are you doing in the executive kitchen?
你觉得我像在干什么  我在管事呢
What does it look like I'm doing? I'm being executive.
但你不是主管
But you're not an executive.
我决定了我自己是  我就是了
Until I made the executive decision that I was.
有什么我能帮你的吗
Now, is there something I can help you with?
有  我想让你先别惦记拿铁
Yeah. I want you to forget that latte
给我搞到自由进出新房子的权利
and get me unfettered access to my new home,
并且把房子前任住户的痕迹
after thoroughly cleansing it
清理得一干二净
of any trace of its former occupants.
你到底为什么想要我这么做
And why, exactly, do you need me to do that?
因为塔拉后天想看房子
Because Tara wants to see the house,
然后我们要共进午餐
and then have lunch with me the day after tomorrow.
路易  你的报价刚被接受
Louis, your offer was just accepted,
在公证史上从来没有
and there's never been a one-day escrow
一天就走完流程的
in the history of escrows.
你以为我不知道吗
You don't think I know that?
我前一个小时一直都在
I just spent the last hour
和五个不同的公证人员周旋
arguing with five different escrow officers.
我明白了
I get it.
你想让我推动人们
You want me to get people to do things
在一段不可能完成任务的时间内
they'd never be willing to do,
做他们永远不想做的事
in a timeframe that makes it impossible for them to do it in.
-完全正确  -那给我弄杯双份拿铁
- Exactly. - Then make me a double latte
然后别在这妨碍我干活
and get the hell out of my way,
因为我将要去执行主管决定
because I'm about to executive decision
让你能进那所房子了
your sorry ass into that house.
你喝什么呢
What are you drinking?
一瓶六十年的世界顶级纯麦威士忌
A 60-year-old bottle of the finest single malt in the world.
给我来一杯
Then get me a glass.
你先告诉我今天法庭上的事再说
Not until I know what happened in court today.
我这么跟你说吧
Well, let me put it this way.
卡荷尔今天晚上唯一能喝的
The only thing that Sean Cahill's gonna be drinking tonight
就是不走运牌的鸡尾酒
is a shit-out-of-luck daiquiri.
你是怎么办到的
How'd you get it done?
我给建立了一个
I established a pattern of him
他习惯没有足够证据就起诉形象
going fishing without enough bait.
那就喝一杯  然后赶紧回去
Then have a drink before you get back in there
让那混蛋再无还手之力
and knock the bastard out before he can throw another punch.
-你什么意思  -我的意思是
- What are you saying? - I'm saying,
我要你直接撤销这个案子
I want you to get this entire action dismissed.
威廉  这不是个好主意
William, that's a terrible idea.
对我来说是  因为他没有任何证据
Not to me, because he's got nothing.
这我不管
I don't care.
你的建议是个大错误
What you're suggesting is a mistake.
你还是没解释为什么
You still haven't told me why.
因为撤诉申请只有一次机会
Because you only get one shot at dismissal,
现在还不到时候
and now's not the time to take it.
我说到了  这不是建议
Well, I say it is. I'm not suggesting it.
我是在命令你这么做
I'm flat out telling you to do it.
我有今天的名声也不是因为被委托人威胁得来的
I didn't get where I am by letting my clients bully me.
我有今天的名声
And I didn't get where I am
也不是屈服于我的雇员得来的
by allowing my employees to dictate terms,
而且今天我已经屈服了一次
which I already did once today.
我不打算再来一次
I'm not gonna do it again.
你什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是杰西卡・皮尔逊今天下午逼我把
It means Jessica Pearson convinced me to give your firm
其余的业务也交给了你们
the rest of my business this afternoon.
所以如果你不去
So if you don't move to
申请撤诉
have the charges against me dismissed,
我就让她代替你
I'll have her do it for you.
哈维  我正要出去
Harvey, I was just on my way out.
你不用出去了
Well, you can be on your way back in,
因为我刚从萨特那回来
because I just came from Sutter's.
看来他告诉你我们聊了两句的事了
I take it he told you about our little conversation today.
如果你所谓的聊了两句的意思是指
If, by conversation, you mean going behind my back
你背着我签了他的投资业务
and getting his investment business,
那么没错  他是告诉我了
then yeah, he told me.
我没有背着你干什么
I didn't go behind your back.
只是看到了一个机遇  采取了行动而已
I saw an opportunity, and I took it.
现在他也看到了一个机遇  采取了行动
Well, now he's seeing an opportunity, and he's taking it.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
他拿你们的合同威胁我
He's leveraging what you did
要我申请撤诉
to get me to move for an immediate dismissal.
我猜猜  你觉得能成功
And, don't tell me, you think it's gonna work?
肯定能成
I sure as hell do.
一旦成功
And the second it does,
迈克出狱的希望也就破灭了
Mike's chance at getting out goes with it,
托你的福
thanks to you.
镇定  小老虎
Hang on there, tiger.
你现在的处境不是因为我做了什么
You're not in this position because of something I did.
而是因为萨特
You're in it because of Sutter,
不管他有没有把业务给我们
and he'd be demanding you have this case dismissed
都会命令你申请撤诉
whether we have his other business or not.
-这不是重点  -不  哈维  重点是
- That's not the point. - No, Harvey, the point is,
我这几天在外面
I have been out there busting my ass
费尽力气给我们拉新业务
trying to find us new business for days,
你知道他们最爱问哪个问题吗
and do you know what they keep asking?
我们为什么还没拿到萨特的投资业务
Why don't we have Sutter's investment business.
一点没错  我们需要拿到它
Goddamn right. We needed it.
于是我拿到了  现在他们都不问了
I got it, and now they're not asking anymore.
那要是我们输掉了官司
Well, what's gonna happen when we lose this case,
失去了他的业务呢
and his business goes away?
到那时  我们已经恢复了元气
What happens is, we're already built back up by then,
所以别再来指责说
so instead of blaming me
是我害你陷入了萨特让你陷入的困境
for the position Sutter has put you in,
我建议你
I suggest you go ahead
想个办法自己解决
and find yourself a way out of it.
瑞秋  有什么事情吗
Rachel, what can I do for you?
我是希望您能为伦纳德・贝利做点事情
I was hoping you could do something for Leonard Bailey.
我拟写了动议  重开他的案子
I drafted a motion to reopen his case,
但我需要一个正式律师递交申请
but I need a current member of the Bar to file it.
你说能监督你办案子的
And what happened to the person you said
那个律师呢
was gonna take this on?
她得等到这周末才有时间
She can't get to it till later this week,
但我想尽快开始
but I want to get on this as soon as possible.
瑞秋  我很抱歉  但我说了
Rachel, I'm sorry, but I told you before,
我现在没有时间精力给这个案子
I don't have the resources to work on this case now.
教授  这个人的妻子放弃了他
Professor, this man has a wife who gave up on him
孩子也见不到面
and children that he doesn't see.
他的整个人生正在离他而去
His entire life is passing him by,
而唯一能给他一个找回人生的机会
and the only way for him to start getting it back
就是有一个人能在意一点
is to just have someone who cares enough about him
腾出半个小时时间做点事
that they give him a half hour of their time.
我看看动议
Let me see your motion.
写得很不错
This is well drafted.
谢谢
Thank you.
但恐怕不会成功
But I'm afraid it won't work.
什么意思  不会
What are you talking--no--
根本就没有理由给他定罪
look, there's no reason that he should have been convicted.
-您看看证据  -这不是重点  瑞秋
- Look at the evidence. - That's not the point, Rachel.
我办过很多这种案子了
I've worked on dozens of these cases,
不管你怎么想  重开旧案的标准
and like it or not, the standard to reopen
实际上比规定高出很多
is higher than what it says in the books.
你需要铁证才行
You need something undeniable.
那我该怎么做
Then what am I supposed to do?
你需要投入精力去找到一个铁证
You're supposed to use your gumption to find that something,
然后才能还他公正
and get Leonard Bailey the justice he's been waiting for.
哈维  很晚了
Harvey, it's late.
不管你来干什么
Whatever you're doing here
都得等到明天再说
is gonna have to wait until morning.
-不行  -为什么
- It can't. - Why's that?
因为萨特要我即刻申请撤诉
Because Sutter wants me to move for an immediate dismissal.
什么
What?
是你让我提出诉讼的
You leveraged me into bringing this indictment,
现在你又要毁了它
and now you want to toss it?
我不想毁掉它  但我要是不申请
I don't want to toss it, but if I don't,
他就会换律师申请
he's gonna find someone else who will.
你来干什么  哈维
What are you doing here, Harvey?
没什么  吃晚餐而已
Nothing, I'm just finishing my dinner.
但是  我不喜欢扔垃圾
The thing is, I don't like to litter,
不如你帮我个忙
so why don't you do me a favor?
要是我走的时候忘了扔
If I forget this when I go,
能不能请你拿上去替我扔了
why don't you take it upstairs and throw it away?
包里放了什么  哈维
What's in the bag, Harvey?
一个包装纸  几张餐巾纸
A wrapper, couple napkins,
还有点薯条
and a few extra fries.
哈维  老实告诉我包里到底放了什么
What the hell is in the bag, Harvey?
放着你需要用来保护案子
What you needed to keep this case going,
而我一直不让你碰的东西
and I stopped you from getting.
妈的  你之前还说你会尽你一切所能
Damn it, you said you were gonna defend him
-帮他辩护  -那也是真的
- to the best of your ability. - And I meant it.
但我当时也知道  如果这和把救出迈克
But I also knew, if push came to shove,
有所冲突的话  我会选择救迈克
I'd do what I had to to get Mike out,
并且我能接受这么做
and I made my peace with it.
-可是我还没有如此觉悟  -你有的
- Yeah, well, I haven't. - Yes, you have.
你到底在说什么
What are you talking about?
你一直给我扯那些不和我共谋之类的调子
You've been giving me this song and dance about not colluding,
而且只要是让你相信我们不共谋的话
and it didn't matter what I said back to you,
无论我怎么回复你都无关紧要了
as long as it was something to let you believe we wouldn't.
因为那些陈词滥调不是为了我好  是为了你好
Because that song wasn't for me, it was for you.
为了我好  狗屁
For me? Bullshit.
这不是狗屁的  肖恩
I don't think so, Sean,
因为你不会只为了仕途晋升
because you don't break a guy out of prison
而帮人越狱
just to advance your career.
这案子对你意义重大
Look, this means something to you.
我不需要知道为什么
I don't need to know what it is,
但是它同样对我意义重大
but it means something to me too,
所以痛快承认我们同一战线
so let's just admit that we're in this together
完成这件事
and get this thing done.
拿走你的垃圾自己扔了
Take that garbage and throw it away.
现在能和我共饮一杯了吗
Now can I have champagne?
你让中介把别墅的钥匙给你了
You got the realtor to give you the key to the house.
不但如此  我还让他决定明天
Not only that, I got him to agree to take the Kellmans
十点到两点带科尔曼斯去
to brunch tomorrow from 10:00 to 2:00
吃庆功早午餐
to celebrate their big sale.
太好了  唐娜
Well, that is great, Donna,
但是我不但需要自由进出这座别墅
but I don't just need to get into the house.
我还要塔拉相信我是别墅的主人  意味着
I need Tara to believe that it's my house, which means--
意味着门上的锁盒不能有
No lock box on the door,
院子里的待售牌子不能有
no for sale sign in the yard,
别墅里的私人物品不能有
and no personal belongings in the house,
因此我们要十点零一分到达那里
which is why we are gonna be there at 10:01
好好把房子布置一下
to stage the shit out of that place.
而且我们要带着这堆东西去
and these are coming with us.
你把布鲁诺的照片重新装裱了
You reframed pictures of Bruno?
配合别墅的样式  是的
In the style of the house.
而且不只布鲁诺
And not just Bruno...
还有米卡多
Mikado.
太棒了  唐娜
That's perfect, Donna.
我只是觉得要让她了解你的为人
I just thought showing Tara your wood
让她看你有什么样的木头不是唯一的方法
wasn't the only way to show her what kind of man you are.
谢谢你  唐娜
Thank you, Donna.
不客气  路易
You're welcome, Louis.
我们居然也用上房间
Since when do we get a room
不用再通过那些低级电话机了
instead of having to use those damn phones?
因为我正式成为你法务团队的一部分了
Since I officially became part of your legal team.
-我的法务团队  -没错
- My legal team? - That's right.
我工作的事务所接下了你的案子
The firm that I work for is taking your case.
这么久以来...
After all this time.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
但是我们还需要想办法重开你的案子
But we still need to get the case reopened,
为此我们需要找新的证据
and to do that we need to find something new.
我们要怎么做
So where do we get that?
我看了案件卷宗
I was going through the state's case file,
里面有审讯记录
and I read your police report.
你说那天晚上你和一个女人待在一起
You said there was a woman with you that night
她能证明你没有杀害那对夫妻
who can testify that you didn't kill that couple.
对的  叫玛利亚
That's right, Maria,
但那不是新的证据
but that's not new.
但对法庭来说它是新证据
Well, it's new as far as the court's concerned,
因为它从未被庭审承认呈供过
because it was never admitted at trial.
那就提交啊
Well, let's admit it.
没那么容易
It's not that easy.
我要知道它当时为何没被承认
I need to understand why it was never admitted.
因为那个女人突然在庭审前玩失踪
Because the damn woman up and disappeared before my trial.
而我的律师也没去想办法
My lawyer didn't do a thing.
你有不在场证明的证人
You had an alibi witness,
然而你的公诉人却让她走掉了
and your public defender let her get away.
我一直都是这么说的啊
That's what I've been saying.
玛利亚本来可以向陪审团证明人不是我杀的
Maria could have told the jury that I didn't do it,
但最后却没了证人
instead no one told them.
两周之后  我就被关起来了
Two weeks later, I'm in here,
时至今日我仍然被关在这里
and I've been here ever since.
你还有其他什么事情没有告诉我吗
Is there anything else I need to know?
那我就得去找玛利亚・戈麦斯了
Then I need to find Maria Gomez.
拜托  我现在真的不想说话
Look, man, please, I really don't want to talk.
没问题  因为是我有话要说
Good, 'cause I want you to listen.
我小时候  我以为我们过得还不错
When I was a kid, I thought we had it good.
也确实还行
And we did.
有好的房子  好的邻居
Had a nice house, nice neighborhood.
除了一件事
Except for one thing.
原来我的父亲
Turns out my father...
是个罪犯
was a criminal.
某一天他被抓了  蹲了监狱
One day he got caught. He went to prison.
我的生活因而分崩离析
My whole life fell apart.
你当时多大
How old were you?
15岁
15.
我告诉你
I'll tell you something.
我因为恨那个人毁了我的生活
I hated that man for doing what he did to me,
做了生活一团糟的15岁少年都会做的事
so I did what messed up 15-year-olds do.
-行为乖张  -乖张
- Started acting out. - Acting out?
兄弟  我当时的前景比这惨多了
Brother, I was on my way to a place worse than this.
最终  我妈妈强迫我去看心理医生
Finally, my mom made me see someone,
他让我意识到  如果当时我不做出改变
and he helped me realize that if I didn't change,
我会毁了自己的一生
I was gonna ruin my life.
因此我力求改正  把生活转向了正常轨道
So I straightened out and turned my life around.
这就是你选择这份职业的原因
And that's why you do what you do.
是的
Yeah.
你为什么要跟我说这些
Why are you telling me this?
因为那个人说服了我是因为
Because the way that man got through to me
他向我打开了自己的心扉
was to open up about himself,
我意识到如果我真的想要帮你
and I realized that if I really want to help you,
我也得这样做
I got to do the same.
好吧  我已经在尽力拖延了
All right, I dragged this out as long as I can,
但这个动议真的拟的差不多了
but I'm pretty much done drafting this motion.
所以我要你递交...
So I'll need you to proof it--
哈维  在那之前
Harvey, before I do that,
我想你得看看这个
I think you should take a look at these.
-什么  -卡荷尔申请了传票
- What is it? - Cahill issued subpoenas
要对威廉・萨特和凯文・米勒进行取证
to deposition William Sutter and Kevin Miller.
这个卑鄙的杂种
That sneaky son of a bitch.
你笑什么
Why are you smiling?
因为昨晚我去找了卡荷尔
Because last night I went to Cahill
想把萨特的交易程序给他
and tried to give him Sutter's trading program.
你做了什么
You did what?
这是我认为唯一能让
It was the only way I could see
这个案子不被撤销的方法
to stop the case from getting dismissed,
但是他没接受
but he wouldn't take it.
而这能给你争取时间
And this buys you time.
是的  前提是法官等卡荷尔
It does, if the judge waits to rule on our motion
取证完之后再判决我们的动议
until after Cahill conducts these depositions.
哈维  即使这样有用
Harvey, even if that works,
要是卡荷尔不能取证到足够的证据
what if Cahill doesn't get enough from the depositions
以让案件不被撤销呢
to keep the case alive?
那迈克出狱的机会也就没了
Then Mike's chance of getting out of prison is gone,
也就意味着要利用这个机会
which means Cahill's not the only one
得到点结果的人不只卡荷尔一个人
that needs to use this to try and get something.
我得承认  赞恩小姐
I have to admit, Ms. Zane,
当你说要查看贝利的案子
when you said you were looking into the Bailey case,
真是激起了我的好奇心
my interest was piqued.
这是很久以前的案子了
That was a long time ago.
明显你不做公设辩护人
Well, you've obviously come a long way
过得好了很多
since your public defender days.
在这种工作里你几乎看不到什么人性美好
You don't exactly see the best of humanity at that job,
这也就让你不能坚持很久
which makes it one you can only do for so long.
但你肯定不是来给我心理治疗的
But you didn't come here to be my therapist.
不  我想谈谈玛利亚・戈麦斯
No, I came to talk about Maria Gomez.
她怎么了
What about her?
我很好奇在有一个能做
I'm curious as to how you can have
不在场证明证人的前提下
an alibi witness on a murder case,
你的委托人还是成了死囚犯
and your client ends up on death row.
因为我并没有一个能做不在场证明的证人
Because I didn't have an alibi witness.
证人凭空消失了
I had a no-show who vanished into thin air,
而我也没有办法找到她
and I didn't have the resources to find her.
你也没想问问负责的警察为什么
And you didn't think to ask the police at trial
他们没有跟进伦纳德的不在场证明吗
why they didn't follow up on Leonard's alibi?
我想到了
I did think of it,
但他们总是一贯的说辞
and they would have said what they always say,
"每个杀人犯都说自己有不在场证明"
"Every murderer claims to have an alibi,"
如果我都提不出来  他们为什么要跟进
and if I couldn't produce her, why should they?
你至少可以要求延期受审
Well, you could have at least asked for postponement,
来找到她
to have time to find her.
我是可以  只是还有个小问题
And I would have, except for one thing.
我不确定一个有前科的瘾君子
I wasn't sure a drug addict with a prior conviction
能帮到伦纳德・贝利什么忙
would have done Leonard Bailey much good.
这是她的品格问题  跟案件事实无关
That's about her character, not the facts of the case.
她的品格就是案件事实
Her character is a fact of the case,
当我要求她说出事发那时他们
and when I pressed her as to what the two of them were doing
两个人在做什么
at the time of those murders,
她承认说他们磕了冰毒
she admitted they were both on meth,
而且还不是第一次
and it wasn't the first time.
而这也可能跟她为什么没有
Which, by the way, might have something to do with
上庭作证有关
why she never showed up at trial.
你想重开这个案子随你  赞恩小姐
So you can try to reopen this case if you want, Ms. Zane,
但我得提醒你
but I am telling you,
你是在浪费自己的时间
you're wasting your time.
什么情况
What's going on?
情况就是我们时间不多了
What's going on is, the clock's ticking.
萨特想要我把案子撤销
Sutter wants me to get the case dismissed.
-什么  这样的话我就...  -我知道
- What? If that happens, I'll-- - I know.
现在听我说
Now, listen to me.
我为我们争取了一点时间
I bought us a little time,
但我要你做件事
but I need you to do something.
好
Okay.
-什么事  -萨特还不知道这件事
- What is it? - Sutter doesn't know this yet,
但我和他明天会来这里
but he and I are gonna be here tomorrow
帮凯文准备取证流程
to have a practice deposition with Kevin.
所以我要你尽力利用
So I need you to do the best
肖恩・卡荷尔这件事让他们说话
Sean Cahill you have to get them talking.
你要我加入他们吗
You want me in the room?
我不觉得这是个好主意
I don't think that's a good idea.
你没听到我说的吗  我们没有时间了
Didn't you hear me? We're running out of time.
我听到了  但我不觉得现在
I heard you, but I don't think it's a good idea
让我和凯文共处一室是个好主意
for me to be in the same room as Kevin right now.
-酒驾的事情吧  -你早都知道
- The drunk driving. - You knew?
-刚知道  -那你也应该知道
- I just found out. - Well, then you also know
现在不是让我和他称兄道弟的好时候
it's probably not the best time for me to chum up to him.
我不是要你跟他做好哥们儿
I'm not asking you to chum up to him.
我是叫你让他发飙
I'm asking you to piss him off.
-你什么意思  -凯文知道一些事情
- What are you talking about? - Kevin knows something,
但他什么都不说
and he's not talking.
我们可以在这里坐等两年
So we could sit around here for the next two years
等着他主动告诉你  但我们也可以
waiting for him to tell you, or we can light a fire
激怒他  提醒他
under his ass by reminding him
萨特逍遥法外
that Sutter's out there,
而他却在蹲监狱
while he's in here.
你到底同不同意
Now, are you with me or not?
同意
I'm with you.
我想你是来告诉我好消息的吧
I take it you're here to give me the good news.
-恐怕不是  -我还以为我说清楚了
- I'm afraid not. - I thought I made myself clear.
如果你不提交动议撤销这个...
If you don't make a motion to dismiss this--
我已经提交了撤销动议
I did file a motion to dismiss,
但这并没什么用
but it doesn't matter,
因为卡荷尔提交了传票申请
because Cahill filed subpoenas
要向你和你女婿取证
to depose you and your son-in-law first,
在取证结束前
and until those depositions happen,
法庭都不会对动议做裁定
the court won't file on the motion.
该死
Goddamn it.
他怎么就知道在我们
How the hell did he know to do that
正要撤销案子的时候想到用这个办法的
when we're about to have the case thrown out?
我不知道  但我过来不是和你讨论这个的
I don't know, but that's not what I came here to talk about,
因为我们得把你和凯文・米勒
because we need to get you and Kevin Miller
弄到一个房间里来准备你俩的供词
in a room to prepare you for your deposition.
你想让我们去监狱
You want us to go to prison?
我想不到别的办法了
I don't see any other choice,
所以你现在最好打电话
so you should call whoever it is
给你今天早上约好要见的人
you were gonna meet this morning
告诉他们你来不了了
and tell them you can't make it,
因为你和我要去一趟丹伯里联邦监狱
because you and I are going to Danbury.
你是真的想帮我吗
Were you really serious about wanting to help me?
为什么我觉得这不是个单纯的问题
Why do I get the feeling that's not a simple question?
因为我想知道你是不是愿意给我查看
Because I want to know if you're willing to give me access
某些记录的权限
to certain records.
抱歉  迈克  我不能泄露其他囚犯的信息
I'm sorry, Mike, I cannot give information on other inmates.
没关系  因为我想找的不是
That's okay, because those aren't the records
那些记录
I'm looking for.
你找到玛利亚了吗
Did you find Maria?
其实  我还没开始找她
You know, I haven't even started looking for her yet,
因为你骗了我
because you lied to me.
什么
What?
我没跟你撒谎
I didn't lie to you about shit.
但你显然也没告诉我你和玛利亚
Well, you certainly didn't tell me that you and Maria
在谋杀发生当晚嗑药嗑嗨了
were high the night of those murders.
-谁跟你说的  -乔治娜・凯西
- Who told you that? - Georgina Casey.
你去见我之前的律师了
You went to see my old lawyer?
是的  没错
Yes, I did.
所以你现在坐在那边看着我就好像在说
And now you sitting over there looking at me like,
"谁知道  也许那些人真的是他杀的"
"You know, maybe he could have killed those people after all."
伦纳德  我去会面之时
Leonard, when I went into that meeting,
是站在你这一边的
I was on your side.
而会面结束之后你就改变立场了
And you came out of it off it.
不  当那场会面结束  我产生了疑问
No, when I came out of it, I had questions.
好啊  那就问啊  我没什么好藏的
Okay, ask them. I got nothing to hide.
真的吗  因为你上次就有事瞒着我
Really? Because you hid something from me the last time.
那不一样
That was different.
-不  那是相关事实  -不  不是的
- No, it's relevant. - No, it isn't.
谋杀发生当晚你嗑药嗑嗨了
You were high the night of the murders,
而你却撒谎没跟我说
and you lied to me about it.
因为我对过去的我感到羞愧
Because I'm ashamed of how I used to be.
我曾是个高中辍学毫无前途的孩子
I was a high school dropout on my way nowhere,
所以  是的  当我找到自己可以承受的起的
so, yeah, I looked for an escape
逃避方式的时候我就选择逃避了
when I could afford one.
我并没有说我没有犯错
I'm not saying I didn't make some mistakes
或者可能甚至还犯了一些罪
or maybe even commit a few crimes,
但我绝对没有杀害那些孩子
but killing those kids was not one of them.
事实就是这样  但我猜现在也无所谓了
And that's the truth, but I guess it doesn't matter,
因为如果你找不到玛利亚
because if you don't find Maria,
总有一天他们会把我送上刑场
someday they're gonna walk me down that hall
给我执行死刑
and put me to death.
那我猜我最好还是赶紧回去找到她
Then I guess I better get back to finding her.
但是  伦纳德  我跟你说清楚
But, Leonard, I'm telling you,
如果你不跟我坦诚一切
if you're not straight with me,
这案子就没法进行下去了
this isn't gonna work.
我绝对不会再隐瞒任何事了
Then I won't ever leave anything out again.
这太荒谬了  这孩子不是肖恩・卡荷尔
This is ridiculous. This kid's no Sean Cahill.
这孩子曾让肖恩・卡荷尔看起来像个傻瓜
This kid made Sean Cahill look like a fool
而他甚至还没有法学学位
without even having a law degree.
我得说一下  当你攻击对方律师的时候
Just so you know, when you attack opposing counsel,
会让你看起来是在害怕
it kind of makes you look afraid.
我可不怕你
I'm not afraid of you.
好的  那么你何不告诉我
Okay, then why don't you tell me this,
坐拥如此多的财富最棒的一点是什么
what's the best thing about having so much money?
-什么  -你听到我说的了
- What? - You heard me.
你在曼哈顿有间顶层公寓
You got the penthouse in Manhattan.
你在南法有座度假别墅  你有两艘游艇
You got the villa in the south of France. You get two yachts--
-那又怎么样  -那又怎么样
- So what? - So what?
所以我是不会想要放弃这一切的
So I wouldn't want to give all of that up.
你会吗  米勒先生
Would you, Mr. Miller?
-我  -是的  你
- Me? - Yeah, you.
我是说  你也能使用这些资产
I mean, you had use of all of these places too,
直到你因为酒驾抛弃了这所有一切
until you threw it all away driving drunk, that is.
-什么  -反对
- What? - Objection.
-与本案无关  -我觉得非常有关
- Irrelevant. - I think it's very relevant.
谁知道  也许凯文也跟财产有关呢
For all I know, Kevin could be somehow involved.
-真是荒唐  -这荒唐吗
- That's insane. - That's insane?
你是交易软件的开发者
You're the developer of the trading software.
我不是那个要受审的人
And I'm not the one who's on trial here.
那我们就来聊聊要受审的这位
Then let's talk about the one who is.
对于你岳父在你入狱期间从来没有前来探视
How do you feel about the fact that your father-in-law
这个事实你感觉如何
never came to visit you in prison?
-什么  -你听到我说的了
- Excuse me? - You heard me.
他从来没有探视过你  你什么感觉
He hasn't come to see you once. How does that make you feel?
对我来说无所谓
It doesn't matter to me.
他可能躺在法国里维埃拉的沙滩上
He could be lying on a beach in the French Riviera,
而你却几乎见不到你的老婆孩子
while you can barely see your wife and kids,
这样你也无所谓吗
and that doesn't matter to you?
米勒先生的家人和本案调查无关
Mr. Miller's family has nothing to do with this investigation.
米勒先生的家人就是本案调查的对象
Mr. Miller's family is the subject of this investigation,
而他的岳父很显然对此毫不关心
and his father in law clearly doesn't give a shit--
我很感激凯文为我做的一切
I'm grateful for everything Kevin's done for me,
-他也知道的  -嗯  我信了
- and he knows it. - Yeah, right.
抱歉  你刚说什么
I'm sorry, what was that?
你是不是想反驳他对你很感激这个说法
Are you disputing the fact that he's grateful to you?
我不会回答这个问题的
I'm not answering that question.
这根本毫无进展
This isn't getting us anywhere.
他在为你应对卡荷尔做准备
He's getting you ready for Cahill.
我本不需要为应对卡荷尔做准备
I wouldn't have to get ready for Cahill
如果你能尽职尽责把这件案子给撤销掉
if you did your goddamn job and got this case dismissed.
没错  就像你一直以来的做法一样
That's right, get someone else
找其他人来收拾你的烂摊子
to cover up your mess like you always do.
你是有什么想说的话吗
You got something you want to say to me?
我是有什么想对你做的事
I got something I want to do to you.
你最好给我记好了你是在和谁说话
You better remember who you're talking to.
我很清楚我是在和谁说话
I know exactly who I'm talking to,
就是那个只顾自己
the guy who doesn't give a shit
不顾他人的自私鬼
about anyone else other than himself.
-够了  -是够了
- That's enough. - That is enough.
要受审的是你
This is your trial.
不是我  我已经受够这些
It's not mine, and I'm done with this,
也受够你了
and I'm done with you!
警卫
Guard.
混账东西
Son of a bitch.
我就知道那小子是个麻烦
I knew that kid would be a problem.
镇定  我把迈克叫来也是这个原因
Relax. That's the whole reason I wanted Mike in here.
如果凯文在打什么歪主意
If Kevin gets any funny ideas,
迈克会先把他稳住  再通知我们的
Mike's gonna calm him down and let us know.
看来你们真的对彼此恨之入骨啊  不是吗
You guys really get under each other's skin, don't you?
你不知道我有多少次
You have no idea how many times
想一拳打在那自鸣得意的老脸上
I thought about punching that bastard in his smug face.
我猜他也很想打你吧
I'm guessing he's thought about punching you too.
你这话什么意思
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
意思是他女儿嫁给了一个罪犯
It means his daughter married a criminal.
-他还不得不接受这个事实  -我告诉你
- He's got to live with that. - You know what?
我也受够了你不停的
I've had just about enough of you
因为我犯的罪讽刺我
giving me shit for what I did.
也许你跟我说实话
Well, maybe I'll stop giving you shit
我就不会再讽刺你了
when your story starts adding up.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你说你是因酒驾被判了三年
You said you got three years for drunk driving,
但你没有前科
but you got no priors,
受害人还一点事儿都没有
and this guy made a full recovery.
百分之九十九的可能你应该能申请缓刑
99 times out of 100, that means you're getting probation.
那看来我的律师很烂咯
Then I guess I had shitty representation.
胡扯
Bullshit.
你这样的有钱人是不会请烂律师的
Money like yours doesn't buy shitty representation.
那不知道还能跟你说什么
Then I don't know what to tell you.
不如开始把真相告诉我啊
How about you start with telling me the goddamn truth?
你想知道真相吗  那我就告诉你
You want to know the truth? I'll tell you,
因为我也不想再藏着掖着了
because I'm sick of holding it in, man.
我被判三年  是因为检方让我告发他的时候
I got three years, because when they offered me a deal
我拒绝了
to turn on him, I said no.
你必须拒绝他们啊  他是清白的
You had to turn them down. He didn't do it.
不  我必须拒绝他们
No, I had to turn them down,
是因为涉案的不止他一个
because he's not the only one involved.
什么
What?
你问我当晚喝酒的原因
You asked me why I was drinking that night.
我喝酒是因为我发现长久以来不断努力
It was because I found out the thing that I worked so hard on
想到得到那自恋狂的认同的做法不过是谎言
to get that prick's approval was nothing but a lie.
-你的那个交易软件  -没错  我的软件
- Your trading program. - Yeah, my program.
到头来他根本就没用
Turns out he wasn't using it at all.
他其实一直都在内幕交易
He was just insider trading the whole time.
好  所以等你回家了  把这事告诉吉尔
Okay, so you got home, you told Jill,
她却不相信你
and she didn't believe you.
不  迈克
No, Mike.
她不只相信我  她...
She not only believed me, she...
她早就知情了
she already knew.
她参与了
She was in on it.
没错
Yeah.
所以我跑出家门  喝得酩酊大醉
So I went out, and I got drunk.
等我恢复意识了
And the next thing I knew,
发现要不然自己在牢里蹲三年
I had to choose between going to prison for three years,
要不然孩子们就再也见不到他们的妈妈了
or the mother of my children going away for a whole lot more.
凯文  你得...
Kevin, you got--
好了  我已经抹去了
Okay, I have removed
凯尔曼一家在这里生活的所有痕迹
every possible trace of the Kellmans' existence
并且全部替换成你的风格了
and replaced it with yours.
我现在要做的就是往冰箱里塞满西梅汁
Now all I have to do is fill the refrigerator with prune juice,
接着设置好...
and then I've got to set up the--
-好了  出去  -什么
- Okay, get out. - What?
出去是什么意思  我得设置好...
What do you mean get out? I haven't set up the--
她把车停好了  她要到了
She's pulling up. She's here,
我不想让她看到我们呆在一起
and I don't want her to see us together
然后误会我们
and get the wrong idea.
-能产生什么误会  -好了  你难道还不懂吗
- And exactly what idea is that? - Okay, don't you understand?
没有女人比得过你
No woman could compete with you,
只要她认为你我有一丝机会
if she thought there was even a chance
成为情侣
of you and I being together.
-真的吗  -假的  她完爆你十条街
- Really? - No, she blows you away.
现在  赶紧给我出去  从便门走
Now, get the hell out, and use the service entrance.
塔拉  你来啦
Tara, you're here.
天呐
Oh, my God.
路易  这里真是太美了
Louis, this place is wonderful.
你拥有这套房子多久了
How long have you had it?
世代都住在这里  我曾祖母
Had it for generations. Great-grandma Litt,
常常在炉火边织毛衣
she used to make wool right over there by the fire.
这里的采光真是太完美了
The natural light is phenomenal.
完美
Phenomenal.
窗外的景色充斥着野性之美
And there's a wildness to the landscape,
和自由自在的气息
an uninhibited energy.
野性  自由自在
Wild. Uninhibited.
这里太适合我们了  路易
It's perfect for us, Louis.
很高兴你喜欢
I'm glad you like it.
不止喜欢  我是爱这里
I don't just like it. I love it.
正如我爱你一样
Just like I love you.
塔拉  我爱你...
Oh, Tara, I love you--
-什么  -的主意
- What? - It.
你的主意...就是你之前说的那个
Your idea...what you were talking about earlier.
-什么主意  -发生什么了
- Which idea? - What happened?
路易  你没事吧
Louis, are you okay?
这是怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
什么事都没有
Nothing's going on here.
你们跑到我家来干什么
What the hell are you doing in my house?
-你家吗  -路易  他们是谁
- Your house? - Louis, who are these people?
你说的他们就是这套房的
These people are the registered owners
登记持有人
of this property.
就是这套你说你们家
You mean the one you said had been
世世代代都住在这儿的房子吗
in your family for generations?
他说谎  我们亲手建的这套房
That's a lie. We built this house ourselves,
直到五分钟之前  我们还想卖给他的
and until five minutes ago, we were gonna sell it to him.
塔拉  听我解释
Tara, I can explain.
我不想听你解释  我已经听够了
I don't need you to explain. I've heard enough.
塔拉  请等一下
Tara, wait. Please.
塔拉  等一下
Tara, please wait.
你知道吗  我听说过你这样的人
You know, I've heard about people like you.
你想从我这得到免费的设计建议
You're trying to get free design work out of me,
然后再决定要不要买这栋房子
so you can decide whether or not you want to buy this house.
事情完全不是这么回事
That has nothing to do with it.
是吗  因为一开始
Really? Because, first,
你就想让我开工
you tried to get me to work on this
却又不带我看实物
without even seeing the space.
然后又找借口把我骗到这来
Then you lured me out here under false pretenses.
所以不如你来告诉我到底是怎么回事
So why don't you tell me what, exactly, is going on here?
我对你撒谎说我在汉普顿斯有房子
I lied to you about owning a house in the Hamptons
这样我就有机会多和你在一起
so I could spend time with you.
什么  你为什么要这么做呢
What? Why--why would you do that?
因为你如此的完美  漂亮
Because you are perfect, and beautiful,
智慧而又有才华
and intelligent, and talented,
而且我完全配不上
and so far out of my league.
这是我唯一能想到的争取一些时间
It was the only thing that I can come up with to find the time
让你爱上我的办法
I needed to make you fall for me.
你竟然愿意为此买一栋房子并重新装修
You were willing to buy and remodel an entire house to do that?
是的
I was.
这是我听过最浪漫的事了
That's the most romantic thing I've ever heard.
-真的吗  -是的  真的
- Really? - Yeah. Yes, really.
塔拉  你愿意和我一起吃饭吗
Tara, would you like to have dinner with me?
我很愿意  路易
I'd love to, Louis.
你在忙什么
What are you working on?
在处理一份委托书
An engagement letter.
你找到了一个新客户
You got a new client.
我给律所找了两个客户
I got us two new clients.
这就是你前几天要处理的事
So that's what you had to do the other day.
差不多吧
Well, something like that.
前几天找到的客户今天又给我介绍了一个
The one I got the other day led to the one I got today.
那很棒
That's great.
是啊  你有什么事
Yeah, what's on your mind?
我知道你说过这周晚些时候
I know you said that you'd give me
你会抽出一个小时留给我
an hour of your time later this week,
但我今天晚上就要用
but I need that hour tonight.
瑞秋  今天我很累了
Rachel, it's been a long day.
我们能早上再聊吗
Can we talk about this in the morning?
不行杰西卡  我等不了了
No, Jessica, we can't.
伦纳德・贝利的处决日期已经定下来了
Leonard Bailey's execution date's been set,
我不知道要怎么跟一个人说他马上就要死了
and I don't know how to tell a man that he's going to die.
你知道  我一直都清楚
You know, I always knew
吉尔和我是不同世界的人
that Jill and I were from two different worlds.
她是萨特家的人  而我只是
And she was a Sutter, and I was just--
一个只擅长与数字打交道
A guy who was good with numbers
除此之外别无所长的人
and didn't have much else?
原以为她明白这一点
Figured it was only a matter of time
只是时间问题
before she came to her senses,
但她从未后悔过
but she never did.
我猜猜  威廉一直不接受你和吉尔在一起
Well, let me guess, William never accepted it.
对  所以当他要求我开发那种算法
No. So when he asked me to develop that algorithm,
我想  我的机会来了
I thought, "This is my chance."
当我把算法给他时  他十分自豪
And when I gave it to him, he acted so proud.
开始称我为他的乘龙快婿
Started calling me his genius son-in-law.
但其实我只是世上最大的傻瓜
But I was really just the world's biggest sucker,
因为我让那个混蛋骗了我
because I let that son of a bitch get one over on me,
我余生都会为此后悔不已
and I'll regret it for the rest of my life.
要是你也能骗他一次呢
What if you could get one over on him?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你自己说过他们想跟你交易
You said yourself, they offered you a deal.
我打赌他们仍然愿意接受
I bet they'd still take it.
不可以  如果我把他抖出来
No way. If I give them him,
他们会追查到吉尔
they go after her.
如果你让他们先给吉尔豁免权就不会了
Not if you get them to give Jill immunity first.
-不行  -凯文  你必须这么做
- No. - Kevin, you have to--
这太冒险了
It's too big a risk,
而且你还是我岳父的律师
and you're my father-in-law's lawyer.
你不该说这种话
You can't be saying this.
我谁的律师也不是
I am nobody's lawyer,
我是你的朋友  我只是说
I am your friend. And I am saying--
我说不行  我要你现在保证
Well, my answer's no, and I want your word, right now,
你不会把我跟你说的告诉别人
that you won't tell anyone what I told you.
-拜托凯文  你别  -迈克  我说真的
- Kevin, please, you're not-- - Mike, I'm serious.
不许让别人知道我告诉你的事情
No one can ever know anything about what I told you.
我向你保证
You have my word.
我有跟你说过我妈妈是个老师吗
Did I ever tell you my mother was a teacher?
一年级老师
First grade.
人人都说她是他们孩子有过的
Everybody always said she was the best teacher
最好的老师
their kid ever had.
她也很开心
She loved it.
她一直都梦想着退休后可以到西班牙去看看
She also always dreamed of seeing Spain when she retired.
本来六年前就可以的
That was supposed to be six years ago,
但当时的州立教师养老基金
but then the state teacher's pension fund
决定把钱投给威廉・萨特
decided to invest its money with William Sutter
她去年在工作中去世了
She died last year, still working.
每一年  我都想花钱让她去旅行
And every year, I tried to pay for her trip,
但她一直拒绝
but she just wouldn't let me.
肖恩  你为什么跟我说这个
Sean, why are you telling me this?
因为法官还是决定撤销你的案子了
Because a judge decided to rule on your motion to dismiss after all.
这意味着我们没有时间了
Which means we're out of time,
所以你来不是为了给我讲你母亲的故事的
and you didn't just come here to tell me about your mother.
是的  我来问你要那个交易程序
No. I came here to ask for that trading program.